Guide to the Eritrea Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Eritrea collection
1942-1997
MS 1515
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.02
(6 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political and social conditions in Eritrea and a photograph album of life in Eritrea.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political and social conditions in Eritrea and a photograph album of life in Eritrea.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Women -- Eritrea; Eritrea -- Politics and government; Eritrea -- Social conditions; Photographs -- Eritrea; Hezbāwi genbār ḥārenat ʼÉretrā; Tagādlo hārnat ʼÉrtrā
- Inventory
  - Eritrean Liberation Front (ELF): journals; newsletters; printed material, 1976-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Union de Lucha Marxista Leninista: printed material, [1984?] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Eritrean People's Liberation Front (EPLF): journals; newsletters; printed material, 1977-1989, [1994?], undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Eritrean liberation and relief organizations: printed material, 1978-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Eritrean Relief Committee/Association: journals; newsletters; printed material, 1986-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Eritrea Update: journal published by the Provisional Government of Eritrea (EPLF), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Birth of a Nation: journal of information published by the Government of Eritrea, Department of External Affairs, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Eritrean Women's General Union: first congress transcript, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - United Nations: special report on Eritrea, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, Accession 1995-M-143
  - Additional printed materials, 1945-1953, 1977-1978, 1982, 1988-1997, undated (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 1997-M-164
  - Life in Eritrea [photograph album, 2nd edition], 1942 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 2004-M-046
  - Eritrea in Relief [newsletter of Eritrean Relief Association (ERA)], 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Eritrea Information [bulletin of Research and Information Centre on Eritrea (RICE)], 1981, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Eritrea Now [newsletter of Eritrean People's Liberation Front European Office], 1980 Feb, Jul/August (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Eritrean Relief Committee (ERC) [appealletters, newsletters], 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Liberation [bulletin of Eritreans for Liberation in North America (EFLNA)], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Resistance [newsletter of National Union of Eritrean Students (NUES)], 1979, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified newsletter, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional Material, 1992, 1994; Accession 2010-M-104
  - Eritrea Profile, 1994 September-October (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Eritrea Update, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1979-1980; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)